Guide to the Mary McCarthy Papers, circa 1915-2013 (bulk 1960-1989)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES V: PERSONAL CORRESPONDENCE
  - Personal correspondence to and from Mary McCarthy
    - Haskell, Francis, 1955-1957 (Folder 352.27)
    - Haskell, Francis, 1958-1985, undated (Folder 199.5)
    - Hatch, Francis (Frank), 1971-1987, undated (Folders 199.6 - 199.7)
    - Hatfield, Mark O., 1981 (Folder 199.8)
    - Hauser, Ernest, 1971-1986, undated (Folder 199.9)
    - Hauserman, B. Strong (Folder 345.40)
    - Haynes, Jim, 1977-1987 (Folder 199.10)
    - Hayworth, R., 1975 (Folder 200.1)
    - Heinemann, William (Folder 345.41)
    - Hélion, Jean and Jacqueline, 1972-1986, 1989, undated (Folders 200.2 - 200.3)
    - Hell, José, 1965-l986, undated (Folder 200.4)
    - Heller, Erich (Folder 345.42)
    - Hemsing, Esther, 1964, undated (Folder 200.5)
    - Henderson, Pricilla (Folder 345.43)
    - Henderson, Rene, 1978-1979 (Folder 200.6)
    - Henle, James, 1967 (Folder 200.7)
    - Henry, Peggy, 1965 (Folder 200.8)
    - Hertel, Hans, 1968-1986 (Folder 200.9)
    - Hibshman, Mrs. Benjamin T. "Thil" (Folder 345.44)
    - Hicks, Granville (Folder 345.45)
    - Highsmith, Patricia, 1972-1984 (Folder 200.10)
    - Hobson, Wilder (Folder 345.46)
    - Hodgson, Priscilla and Simon, 1983-1988, undated (Folder 200.11)
    - Hofer, Evelyn, 1960-1971 (Folder 200.12)
    - Hofer, Evelyn (Folder 345.47)
    - "Mr. Hogan", (TLS) (Folder 351.6)
    - Hook, Sydney (Folder 345.48)
    - Houghton, Norris, 1963 (Folder 200.13)
    - Howe, Irving (Folder 345.49)
    - Howe, Tom, 1962, undated (Folder 200.14)
    - Hunt, Marion, 1979-1981 (Folders 200.15 - 200.16)
    - Hunt, Marion, 1982-1983, undated (Folders 201.1 - 201.2)
    - Hunt, Marion, 1989 (Folder 352.1)
    - Hunting, Rob and Constance, 1981-1984 (Folders 201.3 - 201.6)
    - Hunting, Rob and Constance, 1985-1988, undated (Folders 202.1 - 202.5)
    - Hunting (Folder 345.50)
    - Inglis, Ian, 1962 (Folder 203.1)
    - Inglis, Ruth, 1964 (Folder 203.2)
    - Iselin, Sally, 1978-1983, undated (Folder 203.3)
    - Isherwood, Chirstopher (Folder 345.51)
    - Jackson, Charles (Folder 345.52)
    - Jackson, David, 1963-1984, undated (Folder 203.4)
    - Jacobson, Dan, 1962-1984, undated (Folder 203.5)
    - Janeway, Eliot (Folder 345.53)
    - Jarell, Randall (Folder 345.54)
    - Javsicas, Gabriel, 1963-1980, undated (Folders 203.6 - 203.7)
    - Jelenski, Kot, 1962-1974 (Folders 203.8 - 203.10)
    - Jelenski, Kot, 1975-1987, undated (Folders 204.1 - 204.6)
    - Jencks, Ruth and Gardner, circa 1950-1966 (Folder 352.28)
    - Jencks, Gardner and Ruth, 1962, undated (Folder 204.7)
    - Jenkins, Peter and Polly, 1974-1976, undated (Folder 204.8)
    - Jenkins, Ruth, 1975-1987, undated (Folder 204.9)
    - Jensen, Oliver (Folder 345.55)
    - Jessup, John K., 1963 (Folder 204.10)
    - Jewett, Jon, 1985-1987, undated (Folder 204.11)
    - Joachim, Hans (Folder 345.56)
    - Johnson, Buffie (Folder 345.57)
    - Johnson, Diane (Folder 345.58)
    - Johnson, Diane ("Dinny"), 1980-1988, undated (Folders 205.1 - 205.2)
    - Jolas, Maria, 1964-1979, undated (Folder 205.3)
    - Jones, Gloria and James "Jim", 1963-1978, undated (Folder 205.4)
    - Jovanovich, William "Bill" (Folder 345.59)
    - Just, Ward and Sarah (Folder 345.60)
    - Kallen, Horace (Folder 346.1)
    - Kallen, Horace (Folder 352.29)
    - Kalstone, David, 1981, undated (Folder 205.5)
    - Kaplan, J. M. (Folder 346.2)
    - Kardiner, Dr. A. (Folder 346.3)
    - Karpinski, Wojciech w/Karpinski typescript draft on Chiaromonte ("Nicola Chiaromonte and His Notebooks"), 1981-1984 (Folder 205.6)
    - Karpinski, Wojciech, 1987 (Folder 205.7)
    - Karpinski, Wojciech (Folder 346.4)
    - Katz, Eugene and Florine (Folder 346.5)
    - Kennan, George (Folder 205.8)
    - Kenney, Susan (Folder 346.6)
    - Kerr, Barbara, 1964-1984, undated (Folder 205.9)
    - Khiel, Hanne, 1950-1960 (Folder 205.10)
    - Kiesler, Frederick and Lillian, 1963-1965, no year (Folder 205.11)
    - Kiessler, Steffi (Folder 346.8)
    - Kilmartin, Terence and Joanna, 1979-1988 (Folder 205.12)
    - King, [Bayard?] Le Roy, 1951, 1954 (Folder 352.2)
    - King, Nicholas, 1957-1985 (Folders 206.1 - 206.6)
    - King, Nicholas, 1986, undated (Folders 207.1 - 207.4)
    - King, Nicholas (Folder 346.7)
    - King, Sally, 1972 (Folder 208.1)
    - King, Susan B., 1979 (Folder 208.2)
    - Kirchwey, Karl (to Margo) (Folder 346.9)
    - Kissinger, Henry, undated (Folder 208.3)
    - Knapp, Willy, 1977 (Folder 208.4)
    - Knapp, W. (Folder 346.10)
    - Knopf, Blanche W., 1963 (Folder 208.5)
    - Koch, Stephen (Folder 346.11)
    - Koehler, Lotte, 1975-1989 (Folders 346.12 - 346.25)
    - Kohler, Lotte, 1981-1988, undated (Folder 208.6)
    - Kohn, Jerome, 1982-1988 (Folder 208.7)
    - Kohn, Jerome (Folder 346.26)
    - Korsbaek, Vagn, 1981 (Folder 208.8)
    - Kott, Janek, 1978-1985, undated (Folder 208.9)
    - Kramer, Jane, 1983, [n.y.] (Folder 208.10)
    - Kristensen, Thorkil, 1975-1981 (Folder 208.11)
    - Kristol, Irving (Folder 346.27)
    - Kronenberger, Louis, 1963-1964 (Folder 208.12)
    - Kruglak, F., undated (Folder 208.13)
    - Kufrin, Joan, 1980-1982, undated (Folder 208.14)
    - Kwok, Mak Ting, 1975-1984 (Folder 210.3)
    - Kwok, Mak Ting (Folder 347.5)
    - Kwok, Mak Ting, 1975-1976 (Folder 352.30)
    - Lafarge, Ben (Folder 346.28)
    - Lamb, John (Folder 346.29)
    - Lamont, Corliss, 22 December 1941 (Folder 352.31)
    - Lasky, Melvin L., 7 October 1955 (Folder 352.33)
    - Lasky, Melvin J., 1961-1967, undated (Folder 208.15)
    - Lasne-Sauvigny, Jacqueline, 1978-1981 (Folder 208.16)
    - Laughlin, James, 1953 (Folder 208.17)
    - Laughlin, James (New Directions) (Folder 346.30)
    - Lawler, Traugott (Yale University) (Folder 346.31)
    - Lawrence, Barbara, 1921, 1981-1987, undated; (10 TLS, 1 postcard, 1 AL, 3 pages from Lawrence's diary, a later description of McCarthy by Lawrence, and one ALS from Carol Brightman to Lawrence) (Folder 208.18)
    - Lawrence, Barbara, 1985-1987 (Folder 208.19)
    - Lazar, Josette, 1964-1982, undated (Folder 208.20)
    - Le Coq, Ann-Marie (College de France) to Robert Silvers, 4 May 1989 (Folder 352.32)
    - Lee, Julie, 1977-1979 (Folder 209.1)
    - Leiper, Maria (Simon And Schuster, Inc) (Folder 346.32)
    - Leithäuser, J. (Folder 346.33)
    - Leman, Gerard (Folder 346.34)
    - Leo, Patsy, 1982-1988, undated (Folder 168.3)
    - Leo, Patsy and Jim, 1989 (Folder 339.4)
    - Levi, Anjo and Mario, 1976-1988, undated (Folder 209.2)
    - Lewis, Anthony, 1971 (Folder 209.3)
    - Lichtheim, George (Folder 346.35)
    - Linton, Matilde (Folder 346.36)
    - Lippmann, Helen (Mrs. Walter), 1967-1970 (Folder 209.4)
    - Lippmann, Walter, 1965-1967, undated (Folder 209.5)
    - Lolringer, L. (Folder 346.37)
    - Longcope, Duncan, undated (Folder 209.6)
    - Low, Virginia (Folder 346.39)
    - Lowell, Alice, undated (Folder 209.7)
    - Lowell, Caroline (later Lady Caroline Blackwood), 1977; (1 letter from M.M.) (Folder 209.8)
    - Lowell, Robert, 1961-1977, undated (Folder 209.9)
    - Lowell, Robert (Folder 346.38)
    - Luthwaite, Peggy, undated (Folder 209.10)
    - Thomas McAllister (Folder 347.13)
    - MacArthur Foundation (Kenneth Hope) (Folder 347.1)
    - McCarn, Louise, undated (Folder 209.11)
    - McCarthy, Eugene, 1969-1973 (Folder 209.12)
    - MacDonald, Dwight, 1957-1982, undated (Folders 209.13 - 209.14)
    - MacDonald, Dwight (Folder 347.2)
    - Macdonald, Nancy, 1952-1984 (Folder 394.6)
    - Macdonald, Nancy (Spanish Refugee Aid, Inc.), 1980-1988 (Folder 209.15)
    - Macdonald, Nicholas and Elspeth, 1965-1979, undated (Folder 209.16)
    - Macfarlane, Libby Kerr, undated (Folder 209.17)
    - McGrath, undated (Folder 209.18)
    - MacIver, Loren, 1968 (Folder 209.19)
    - McKay, Helen, 1969 (Folder 209.20)
    - McKenzie, Alan, 1984-1985 (Folder 209.21)
    - McKinney, Chloe, 1973-1974 (Folder 209.22)
    - McClatchy, J. D., (and 2 associated Princeton letters), 1986 (Folder 352.34)
    - MacNeil, Alain and Esther (Folder 347.3)
    - Maddocks, Arthur (ambassador), 1978-1979, undated (Folder 210.1)
    - Maguire, Peter, 1988, undated (Folder 210.2)
    - Maguire, Peter (Folder 347.4)
    - Mallon, Thomas, 1971-1988, undated (Folders 210.4 - 210.5)
    - Manell, A. E. (The Foreign Service of the U.S.A.) (Folder 347.6)
    - Mariano, Nicholas, 1959-1979 (Folder 211.1)
    - Mariano, Nicky (Folder 347.7)
    - Marignano, Nicky (Folder 347.8)
    - Marlowe, Sylvia (Folder 347.9)
    - Marlowe, S. and L., 1963-1977 (Folder 211.2)
    - Marshall, E. G., undated (Folder 211.3)
    - Marshall, John (Folder 347.10)
    - Marvell ,Thomas, 1954-1958 (Folder 347.11)
    - Maxwell, Bill (The New Yorker) (Folder 347.12)
    - May, Derwent and Yolanta, 1985-1986, no year (Folder 211.4)
    - Meigs, Mary, 1971-1986, no year (Folder 211.5)
    - [Meigs, Mary?] (Folder 352.35)
    - Merrill, James [with David Kalstone], 1961-1980, no year (Folder 211.6)
    - Merrill, James, 1981-1988 (Folder 211.7)
    - Merrill, James (Folder 347.14)
    - Merrill, James [postcard removed from McCarthy's copy of Merrill's From the First Nine PS3525.E6645 F3], 21 October 1982 (Folder 394.1)
    - Meyers, Jeffrey (Folder 347.15)
    - Michielson, Peter, 1985 (Folder 394.14)
    - Michahelles, Rosalind, 1983-1989, undated (Folder 168.4)
    - Michahelles, Rosalind, 1976?-1988, no year (Folder 212.1)
    - Michahelles, Rosalind (Folder 347.16)
    - Middeldorf, Dr. Ulrich (Folder 347.17)
    - Middleton, Derek and Veritas, 1988, no year (Folder 212.2)
    - Milford, Nancy, 1974 (Folder 212.3)
    - Miller, Ed and Ann, 1979-1988, undated (Folder 212.4)
    - Miller, Henry (Folder 347.18)
    - Miller, Ingeborg Morath [photographer], 1962-1963 (Folder 212.5)
    - Millman, Michael [Berkeley Citizens' Committee of Inquiry], 1964 (Folder 212.6)
    - Milosz, Czeslaw, 1965-1986 (Folder 212.7)
    - Misch, Bob (Folder 347.19)
    - Mitchell, Ada, 1961 (Folder 212.8)
    - Mitchell, Burroughs (Folder 347.20)
    - Mitford, Jessica, 1969 (Folder 212.9)
    - Mitford, Nancy, 1968 (Folder 212.10)
    - Moers, Ellen, 1978 (Folder 212.11)
    - Montalvo, Jennette (Folder 347.21)
    - Montenero, Nancy (Fugazy Express) (Folder 347.22)
    - Moore, Marianne (Folder 347.23)
    - Morath, Inge, 13 March 1956 (Folder 352.36)
    - Morel, Paul (Folder 347.24)
    - Morgan, Frederick [Editor, The Hudson Review; wife: Paula Dietz, Assoc. Editor], 1974-1978, undated (Folder 212.12)
    - Mostyn-Owen, William*, Gaia, Owen, Allegra, Orlando [*sec'y to B. Berenson (Gelderman, p. 194)], 1961-1989, undated (Folders 213.1 - 213.8)
    - Mourek, M., 1978, undated (Folder 214.1)
    - Muggeridge, Malcolm, 1962 (Folder 214.2)
    - Mulisch, Harry, 1962-1988 (Folder 214.3)
    - Murphy, Noël, 1968-1981, no year (Folder 214.4)
    - Muser, Frani Blough, 1933-1935; (photocopies of letters from M.M.) (Folder 214.5)
    - Muser, Frani Blough, 1964-1988, undated (Folders 214.6 - 214.9)
    - Muser, Frani Blough, 1949, 1951, 1989, undated (Folder 343.4)
    - Myers, John, 1961-1986, no year (Folder 214.10)
    - Myers, John (Folder 347.25)
    - Nyrdal, Gunnar, 1971-1972 (Folder 214.11)
    - Nabokov, Nicolas, Ivan, and Dominique, 1972-1988, no year (Folder 214.12)
    - Nabokov, Nicholas (Folder 347.26)
    - National Institute of Arts and Letters (Mrs. Mathew Josephson) (Folder 347.30)
    - Niebuhr, Elizabeth, 1961, no year (Folder 215.1)
    - Nomad, Max (Folder 347.27)
    - Nooteboom, Cees, 1964-1988, undated (Folders 215.2 - 215.5)
    - Nooteboom, Cees (Folder 347.28)
    - Norman, Nancy (Folder 347.29)
    - Oates, Joyce Carol, 1980-1983 (Folder 216.1)
    - Oates, Joyce Carol [lnote removed from McCarthy's copy of Oates' The Profane Art PN710.O19 1983], 8 December 1986 (Folder 394.2)
    - Okoye, Chris Okey (Folder 347.31)
    - Olsson, Hanna, 1964-1978, undated (Folder 216.2)
    - Onassis, Jacqueline, (1 telegram) (Folder 352.37)
    - O'Neill, Catherine, 1986-1988, undated (Folder 216.3)
    - O’Neill, Catherine (Folder 347.32)
    - Orlando, Ruggero (Folder 347.33)
    - Ortman, Conni and George, undated (Folder 216.4)
    - Ortmon, Connie (Folder 347.34)
    - Orwell, Sonia [w/some ltrs from Blanchot 21], 1958-1980, undated (Folders 216.5 - 216.8)
    - Orwell, Sonia (Weidenfeld and Nicolson Limited Publishers) (Folder 347.35)
    - O’Shea, Howard Vincent (Folder 347.36)
    - O'Sullivan, Vera, 1980-1981 (Folder 216.9)
    - Palmer, Bob, 1979, undated (Folder 216.10)
    - Palmer, Thomas (Folder 348.1)
    - Paolucci, Anne, 1965-1966 (Folder 216.11)
    - Papi, Roberto (Folder 348.2)
    - Papi, Roberto and Laura, 1957-1962, undated (Folder 216.12)
    - Parenzi, Eleanor (Folder 348.3)
    - Parker, Margaret (Folder 348.4)
    - Passin, Herbert (Folder 348.5)
    - Patterson, Linsay (Folder 348.6)
    - Patterson, Suzy, 1984-1985, undated (Folder 217.1)
    - Paturis, Cleo, 1971-1988, undated (Folders 217.2 - 217.4)
    - Paturis, Cleo, 1975-1988; (photocopies) (Folder 217.5)
    - Pease, Deborah, 1964-1988, undated (Folders 217.6 - 217.7)
    - Pease, Deborah (Folder 348.7)
    - Peden, William (Folder 348.8)
    - Perényi, Eleanor and Grace Stone [mother of Eleanor], 1963-1988, undated (Folders 218.1 - 218.6)
    - Penrose, Edith (Folder 348.9)
    - Perlius, [Helvetia?], 1953, 1959, undated (Folder 218.7)
    - Pham Van Dong, 1970-1979 (Folder 218.8)
    - Phillips, John, 1977-1984 (Folder 219.1)
    - Phillips, John (Folder 348.10)
    - Pieraccini, Roland, 1985 (Folder 394.13)
    - Pillsbury, Henry and Judy, 1984, undated (Folder 219.2)
    - Pirkko-Liisa Stahl, Mrs. — re Nobel Prize, 25 May 1977 (Folder 394.12)
    - Pivano, Fernanda (Folder 348.11)
    - Plimpton, Sarah, 1964-1975 (Folder 219.3)
    - Plimpton, Sarah (Folder 348.12)
    - Pounder, Robert "Bob" (Folder 348.13)
    - Prince, Augusta (Folder 348.14)
    - Pritchett, V. S., [1953] November 22 (Folder 352.38)
    - Privental, Mary (Folder 348.15)
    - Prosser, Margaret (Folder 348.16)
    - Pryce-Jones, Clarissa and David (Folder 348.18)
    - Purcell, Lawrence J. (Folder 348.17)
    - Purdy, James, 1956 (Folder 219.4)
    - Quinby, Pat, 1969-1983, undated (Folder 219.5)
    - Rácz, Judit, 1980-1983, undated (Folder 219.6)
    - Rado, George (Folder 348.19)
    - Rado, Sandor (Folder 348.20)
    - Rahv, Nathalie (Folder 348.21)
    - Rahv, Philip (Folder 348.22)
    - Rahv, Philip, 1957-1973 (Folders 219.7 - 219.8)
    - Rahv, Philip — re Hannah Arendt, 31 October 1963 (Folder 394.16)
    - About Philip Rahv, 1949-1975 (Folder 219.9)
    - Ramsey, Julia [part of The Group], 1964 (Folder 219.10)
    - Randal, Jonathan and Judy, 1972-1983 (Folder 219.11)
    - Rapaczynski, Andrzej, 1969 (Folder 219.12)
    - Rapson, Mary (Rapson Inc.) (Folder 349.1)
    - Razi, Eggie, 1983, undated (Folder 219.13)
    - Recellai, Cristina, circa 1956-1959 (Folder 352.40)
    - Reeves, Richard, 1984-1987, undated (Folder 219.14)
    - Ress, Paul, 1976-1977, undated (Folder 219.15)
    - Rethenberg, Sarah (Folder 349.2)
    - Revel, Jean-François, 1965-1972, undated (Folder 219.16)
    - Reynal, Eugene (Folder 349.3)
    - Riboud, Barbara Chase, 1980-1985, undated (Folder 220.1)
    - Richards, Alun, 1982-1983 (Folder 220.2)
    - Riese, Laure, 1974-1985, undated (Folder 220.3)
    - Riesman, David (The University of Chicago) (Folder 349.4)
    - Rivers, Larry, 1962, undated (Folder 220.4)
    - Rodman, Selden, 1952 (Folder 352.39)
    - Roethke, Ted (Folder 349.5)
    - Romano, Sergio, 1977-1985 (Folder 220.5)
    - Rooney, Padraig, undated (Folder 220.6)
    - Roper, Kay and John, 1984, undated (Folder 220.7)
    - Rorem, Ned, 1973 (Folder 220.8)
    - Rosenbatt, Danny (Folder 349.6)
    - Rosenberg, Beatrice, 1981-1984, undated (Folder 220.9)
    - Rosenberg, Beatrice (Folder 349.7)
    - Rosenberg, Ethel ("Ted") [from MM], 1929-1930 (Folder 220.10)
    - Rosenberg, Harold and Maynatalie Tabak, 1959-1980 (Folder 220.11)
    - Rosenberg, Harold Tabak (Folder 349.8)
    - Rosenberg, Jess [sister of Ethel Rosenberg], 1971-1985 (Folder 220.12)
    - Photocopies of Ted Rosenberg letters (Folder 349.9)
    - Rosenblatt, Aaron (Folder 349.10)
    - Rosenblüth, Milton B. (Folder 349.11)
    - Roth, Philip (Folder 349.12)
    - Roth, Philip, [circa 1986?]-1988 (Folder 221.1)
    - Rothschild, V. Henry (Folder 349.13)
    - de Rothschild, Pauline (Folder 349.14)
    - Rousuck, Emmanuel J. ("Mannie") [d. 1970] w/2 ltrs. from Reuel and Marcia Wilson, 1951-1972, undated (Folders 221.2 - 221.3)
    - Rovere, Richard ("Dick" w/ ltr. re: Rovere from Daniel Patrick Moynihan, 2/8/85, undated (Folder 221.4)
    - Rovere, Richard "Dick" (Folder 349.15)
    - Rowe, D., undated (Folder 221.5)
    - Rowe, Virginia (for Margaret Brenman-Gibson) (Folder 349.16)
    - Rowse, A. L., 1963-1969, undated (Folder 221.6)
    - Rubinstein, Renate, 1965-1979 (Folder 221.7)
    - Rudkin, Mark, 1978-1988, [n.y.] (Folder 221.8)
    - Rukeyser, Muriel, 1971 (Folder 221.9)
    - Rukeyser, Muriel (Folder 349.17)
    - Russell, A. Preston, 1975-1977 (Folder 221.10)
    - Russell, John and Rosamond, 1977-1978, undated (Folder 221.11)
    - Russell, Verity, 1968-1989 (Folder 221.12)
    - Ryckmans, Pierre, 1978 (Folder 221.13)
    - Saarinen, Aline, 1980, 1987, undated (Folder 222.1)
    - Sahl, Hans (Folder 349.18)
    - St. Georges School (William Buell) (Folder 349.19)
    - St. Georges School (Philip Cutler) (Folder 349.20)
    - Sainton, Helen Cole (Folder 349.21)
    - Salk, Jonas, 1978 (Folder 22.2)
    - Salzman, Rita, 1978, undated (Folder 222.3)
    - Sandison, Helen (Folder 349.23)
    - Sarraute, Nathalie, 1963-1973, undated (Folder 222.4)
    - Sartori, Titina, 1956-1964, undated (Folder 222.5)
    - Scarlett, (Bishop) William, 1967-1972 (Folder 222.6)
    - Schaffner, Perdita, 1962-1977 (Folder 222.7)
    - Schapiro, Meyer, 10 December 1948, 1956 (Folder 352.41)
    - Schaum, Suzie (Folder 349.24)
    - Schlesinger (Folder 349.25)
    - Schlesinger, Arthur — McCarthy the New Statesman regarding Schlesinger, 11 December 1951 (Folder 352.42)
    - Schlesinger, Arthur, Jr., 1957-1983 (Folders 222.8 - 222.10)
    - Schlesinger, Arthur, Jr. and Alexandra, 1985-1987, undated (Folder 222.11)
    - Schlesinger, Marian Cannon (Folder 352.43)
    - Schlimer, Irma (Folder 349.26)
    - Schmidt, Albert and Tatyana, 1978-1979 (Folder 222.12)
    - Schneider, Larry (Folder 349.27)
    - Schorer, Mark-Broadwater re: M. M.'s The Oasis, 1949 (Folder 222.13)
    - Schwartz, Delmore (Partisan Review) (Folder 349.28)
    - Scott, Winifred (Folder 349.29)
    - Seidel, Nancy (Folder 349.30)
    - Servadio, Gaia (Folder 349.31)
    - Sessions, Barbara, 1961-1971, undated (Folder 222.14)
    - Shafer, Margaret, 1966-1988, undated (Folders 223.1 - 223.3)
    - Shafer, Margaret, 1946-1989 (Folder 349.32)
    - Shawcross, M., 1975 (Folder 223.4)
    - Shawn, William, 1954 (Folder 352.44)
    - Sheehan, Rhoda, 1967-1970 (Folder 223.5)
    - Sigmund, Barbara Boggs (Folder 349.33)
    - Silone, Ignazio and Darina, 1971-1984, undated (Folder 223.6)
    - Silverman, Nancy, undated (Folder 223.7)
    - Silvers, Robert (Folder 349.34)
    - Silvers, Robert (Folder 352.45)
    - Simoud, Anne-Marie (Folder 349.35)
    - Simpson, Eileen, 1977-1979, undated (Folder 223.8)
    - Sinclair, John G. (Folder 349.36)
    - Singh, Khushwant, 1962-1963 (Folder 223.9)
    - Slobodkin, Selma (Folder 349.37)
    - Sloman, Fred (Folder 349.38)
    - Slonim, Marc (Folder 349.39)
    - Snyder, Ernest M. (Folder 349.40)
    - Sochaeki, Mary (Folder 349.41)
    - Solow, Herbert, circa 1942-1946 (Folder 352.46)
    - Spender, Stephen Matthew, 1959-1968 (Folder 224.1)
    - Spender, Stephen and Natasha, 1969-1974 (Folder 224.2)
    - Spender, Stephen and Natasha w/ 1 ltr from Lizzie Spender, 1975-1981, undated (Folder 224.3)
    - Spender, Stephen and Natasha, 1983-1984, 1986-1989, undated (Folder 224.4)
    - Spender, Stephen (Folder 349.43)
    - Spencer, Ted (Folder 349.42)
    - Sperber, Mannes, 1964 (Folder 224.5)
    - Speyer, Darthea, 1978-1981, [no date, n.y.] (Folder 224.6)
    - Stanesco, Sarina (Folder 349.44)
    - Stanescu, Sarina, 1971-1982, undated (Folders 224.7 - 224.8)
    - Steele, Zella, 1955-1956 (Folder 225.1)
    - Steele, Lilla (Folder 349.45)
    - Steensen, Howard (Folder 349.46)
    - Steinberg, Saul, 1978-1979 (Folder 225.2)
    - Stemans, Werner, 1974-1986 (Folder 225.3)
    - Stemans, Werner, 1987-1988, undated (Folder 225.4)
    - Stevenson, Adlai (Folder 349.47)
    - Stieglitz, Perry, 1968-1987 (Folder 225.5)
    - Stock, Irvin, 1968-1988 (Folder 225.6)
    - Stone, Grace [See f. 218.1-.6.]
    - Strom, Ron, 1974-1984, [no date, n.y.] (Folder 225.7)
    - Stwertka, Eve, 1976-1986 (Folders 225.8 - 225.10)
    - Stwertka, Eve, 1987-1989, undated (Folders 226.1 - 226.2)
    - Stwertka, Eve, 1978, 1987 (Folder 394.9)
    - Stwertka, Eve (Folder 350.1)
    - Stwertka, Eve, 1989 (Folder 351.1)
    - Stwertka, Eve (Folder 351.2)
    - Sulzberger, C.L., 1974-1977 (Folder 226.3)
    - Sutherland, Mary, 1978 (Folder 226.4)
    - Sweeney, John Lincoln and Maire, 1952, undated (Folder 352.47)
    - Swensen, Martin, 1981-1982, undated (Folder 226.5)
    - Symans, Thérèse, 1963-1987 (Folder 226.6)
    - Tagliacozzo, Enzo, 1951-1979 (Folder 226.7)
    - Tamang, Indra Bahadur see Ford, Charles Henri
    - Tanning, Dorothea, 1980, 1987, 1988 (Folder 226.8)
    - Tate, Allen (Folder 351.3)
    - Tax, Meredith, 1964-1968, undated (Folder 226.9)
    - Taylor, Samuel and Suzanne, 1984-1989, undated (Folders 227.1 - 227.2)
    - Telenga, Suzette ("Susan Yorke"), 1950 October 16 (Folder 352.5)
    - Terrell, Carroll F., 1982-1983 (Folder 227.3)
    - Thomas, Harris H. ("Tommy") and Dorothy and Mary, 1971-1982, undated (Folders 227.4 - 227.6)
    - Thomas, Harris H., 30 October 1974 (Folder 352.48)
    - Thomson, Virgil, 1977 (Folder 228.1)
    - Thomson, Virgil (Folder 351.4)
    - Tierney, Helen Gould, 1945-1947, undated (Folder 352.49)
    - Tierney, Helen, 1954, 1988 (Folder 351.5)
    - Tierney, Helen Gould, 1977 (Folders 228.2 - 228.4)
    - Tolman, Leland and Sally, 1973-1977 (Folders 228.5 - 228.7)
    - Tolman, Leland and Sally [one of MM's attorneys], 1978-1983, undated (Folders 229.1 - 229.5)
    - Tomalin, Marie (Mrs. Nicholas), 1973 (Folder 229.6)
    - Tommarchi, Gerry and Victor, 1963-1965 (Folder 229.7)
    - Tree, Marietta, 1964 (Folder 229.8)
    - Trilling, Diana, 1963-1968 (Folder 229.9)
    - Trilling, Diana (Folder 351.7)
    - Tucci, Niccolo, Laura, Deborah, Vieri, Maria, 1960-1974, undated (Folders 229.10 - 229.11)
    - Tucci, Niccolo, 21 February 1989, undated (Folder 352.50)
    - Tuhoy, William (Folder 351.8)
    - Turnbull, Andrew W. (Folder 351.9)
    - Tyler, Parker, 10 May 1944 (Folder 352.51)
    - Tynan, Kenneth and Kathleen, 1966-1972 (Folder 229.12)
    - Updike, John, 1979, undated (Folder 230.1)
    - Vail, Sindbad, 1964 (Folder 230.2)
    - van Lennep, Alexa, 1976-1981, undated (Folder 230.3)
    - van Mierlo, Hans [M.P.], 1975-1983 (Folder 230.4)
    - Vassilikos, Vassilis, 1968-1978, undated (Folder 230.5)
    - Viscusi, Anthony and Margo (Folder 351.11)
    - Viscusi, Anthony and Margo, 1971-1980 (Folders 230.6 - 230.10)
    - Viscusi, Margo, 1981-1988, undated (Folders 231.1 - 231.7)
    - Viscusi, Margo, 1970-1989 (Folders 351.12 - 351.15)
    - Volk, Patty (Folder 351.16)
    - Waldmann, Edward (Folder 351.17)
    - Walker, Adelaide, 1963-1987 (Folders 232.1 - 232.2)
    - Walker, Adelaid (Folder 351.20)
    - Wallingford, Katrina (Folder 351.18)
    - Wallsten, Bob (Folder 351.19)
    - Wanger, Shelley (Folder 351.21)
    - Warner, Becky (Folder 351.22)
    - Warren, Robert Penn (Folder 351.23)
    - Wass, Douglas, 1975 (Folder 232.3)